# **Elias Frey**

frey.ilya.32@gmail.com • +45 91119 377

https://www.linkedin.com/in/eliasfrey/ • https://elias-frey.github.io/portfolio/ B.S. Ingemanns Vej 2, Sønderborg, Denmark



# **Profile**

The combination of diverse hands-on experience complemented by relevant academic knowledge provides me with a comprehensive understanding of various business functions. My skillset paired with a goal-oriented mindset equips me for interdisciplinary positions such as project manager or data analyst.

# **Education**

#### UNIVERSITY OF SOUTHERN DENMARK

# MSc in Engineering, Innovation and Business

- Relevant Coursework: New Business Development; International Marketing; Data Science and Machine Learning; Innovation in Practice; E-Commerce; Finance For Entrepreneurial Engineers
- Relevant Competencies: Business Modeling; Market Analysis; Project Management; Product Development; Management Methodology; Problem-Solving; Critical Thinking; Data Analysis; Research and Innovation; Financial Analysis

#### EXTRACURRICULAR STUDY ACTIVITY

# Below Zero, SDU Talent Program (20 ECTS)

- **Special Focus:** The course aims to develop key competencies for starting and running a sustainable business. During the course I:
  - Learned methods and best practices for successful business venturing
  - Gained access to a wide network of entrepreneurs
  - Received mentoring from professional Business Developers
- **Result:** Developed an innovative business model with an early prototype and reached the finals of the prestigious Venture Cup start-up competition.

# TALLINN UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY

# **BEng in Power Engineering**

- **Thesis:** Cost-Efficiency of Modernizing Electrical Schemes for Overhead Bridge Cranes
- **Relevant Coursework:** Environmental Protection; Electrical Engineering; Entrepreneurship; Applied Statistics
- Relevant Competencies: Project Management; Electrical Design; Renewable Energy Integration

Sønderborg, Denmark [09.2022 - 06.2024]

Odense, Denmark [10.2022 - 06.2023]

Kohtla-Järve, Estonia [09.2016 - 01.2021]

# Experience

# SEABUD (Start-Up) Business Developer & Co-Founder

Remote Work [02.2023 – ...]

- At SeaBud we are developing an innovative organic fertilizer that will
  make the greens on our tables tastier while also mitigating the negative
  effects of conventional agriculture on the environment.
- **Our progress** so far:
  - Developed an innovative multiple-income stream business model
  - Established contacts with potential clients
  - Developed the first prototype
  - Reached finals of national start-up competition Venture Cup
- Being a co-founder implies cross-disciplinary work, which involves tasks ranging from negotiating with strategic partners to making financial projections and R&D.

#### **KONECRANES LLC**

# Engineer

Tallinn, Estonia [10.2018 - 08.2022]

- Overview: Aligned with the company's slogan: "Lifting Not Just 'Things, but Entire Businesses", I offered our clients a complete service of their cranes and other machinery together with practical advice on how production processes can be improved.
- Activities of this multi-functional role included:
  - Troubleshooting industrial equipment (cranes, CNCs, presses, etc.) in order to restore normal production processes for clients
  - Selling modernization/upgrade projects
  - Developing scope of work with clients (B2B)
  - Design of electrical diagrams
  - Project coordination (incl. international)
  - Preparation of price quotes
- Through my close collaboration with different clients, I gathered unique insights into various industries and learned to build trustful customer relations based on professionalism and goodwill.
- **Key competencies**: Customer Trustworthiness, Project Management, Customer-Oriented Business Development, Six Sigma Troubleshooting, Problem-Solving Abilities, Leadership and Responsible Decision-Making

# **ENEFIT SOLUTIONS JSCo**

# **Laboratory Technician**

- Overview: In the laboratory of the biggest powerplant in Estonia, my work was based on maintaining the safe operation of turbo-generators and high-voltage transformers.
- Being responsible for automatic control and protection circuits my tasks included:
  - Inspections
  - Conducting electrical tests
  - Finetuning sensors
  - Troubleshooting malfunctions
- **Key Competencies:** Electrical Knowledge, Safety Protocols, Troubleshooting, Preventive Maintenance, Teamwork, Data Analysis

#### **EASTMAN JSCo**

## Electrician

• Overview: In a chemical factory, I worked in an electrical service team.

Narva, Estonia [04.2018 – 10.2018]

Kohtla-Järve, Estonia [03.2017 – 04.2018]

Due to the dangerous and sometimes hazardous environment of a chemical plant, regular maintenance, and repair of equipment were executed in accordance with strict safety protocols.

#### Key tasks:

- Adhering to safety protocols and ensuring safety for all stakeholders
- Preventive maintenance
- Emergency repairs
- Collaborations with team members and other departments
- Documentation
- **Key Competencies:** Modern Safety Protocols, Cross-Department Collaborations, Troubleshooting, Teamwork

#### STIVIS JSCo

# Mechanic

Muuga, Estonia [04.2016 – 03.2017]

- Overview: At the cargo terminal of the seaport of Muuga, I was responsible for minimizing the downtime of the ship loading-unloading process to help the company avoid demurrage charges.
- Challenge: The first job of my career with this scale of responsibility responsibility. Under stressful conditions and narrow timeframes, I could rely solely on my own skills and wit. Some of the challenges included:
  - Troubleshoot the reason why machinery stopped the production process
  - Develop a comprehensive plan of required actions, taking into account available resources
  - Efficiently execute the plan and restore the loading/unloading process
- **Result:** I learned all the electrical schematics by heart, developed appropriate troubleshooting methodology, identified the most common breakdowns, and prepared all supplies that were necessary to respond quickly. A few weeks into this new position I was able to comfortably secure the continuous work process of a terminal.
- **Key competencies:** Troubleshooting, Ability to navigate under stress; Problem-Solving, Technical Literacy

# **Leadership and Activities**

# HANDELS-KOLLEGIET Board Member

Sønderborg, Denmark [01.2023 – ...]

- Organizing social events
- Allocating budget
- Improving staying experience for residents

### SUSTAINABILITY ACADEMY

# **Selected Participant**

- Overview: The summer school with guest lectures from Danish authorities and leading scientists in the field of sustainability. The focus was on addressing global and local climate change challenges and exploring potential solutions.
- **Result:** Designed a small project to raise awareness of waste sorting through an interactive trash disposal experience.

Odense, Denmark [06.2023 - 07.2023]

# **Skills**

Python	$\bullet$ $\bullet$ $\bullet$ $\bullet$ $\circ$	Office365 ● ● ● ○
SQL	$\bullet$ $\bullet$ $\circ$ $\circ$ $\circ$	HTML and CSS ● ● ○ ○ ○
PowerBI	$\bullet$ $\bullet$ $\bullet$ $\circ$ $\circ$	C++ ● ○ ○ ○ ○
Excel	$\bullet$ $\bullet$ $\bullet$ $\bullet$	ChatGPT ● ● ○ ○

# Language:

- Fluent in English, Estonian, and Russian (Native language: Russian)

- Currently learning Danish for both cultural and career interests

**Driving Licence:** European Driver's License in categories A and B

# **About**

For me, business always takes the front seat, so it's work before play. However, when it does come to my free time, I am a proponent of a healthy lifestyle, which helps me to stay ready for everyday challenges and stay fit both mentally and physically. I'm a regular at the local gym and follow a good Estonian tradition of saunas and cold plunges. When I'm not sweating it out at the gym or in the sauna, I'm diving into books, tuning into podcasts, and immersing myself in music, which is a huge part of my life. In general, I'm always up for new experiences, be it DJing, riding motorcycles, or exploring embedded software.